<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Me &amp; Life</title>
    <link>http://karlaustin.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Me &amp; Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://karlaustin.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>cP1Con Edinburgh</title>
      <link>http://karlaustin.com/post/cp1con-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://karlaustin.com/post/cp1con-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-background:ad21b4405288ae442b579089103a7bf3&#34;&gt;Some Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day job is providing web hosting, basically lots of computers connected to the internet via the network we run, people then place their websites on the servers so the whole world can see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make that easier for us and for our customers we have some nice control panel software that allows people to set up their email addresses, their out of office, configure the settings for their website, create databases for their website etc. etc.   That software is 

    
        
    

    &lt;a href=&#34;http://cpanel.com&#34; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;cPanel&lt;/a&gt;

, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of software we&amp;rsquo;ve been using since late 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-conferences:ad21b4405288ae442b579089103a7bf3&#34;&gt;The Conferences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 10 years cPanel have run an annual conference in the USA, it&amp;rsquo;s where they are based and where most customers are, it&amp;rsquo;s a technical event and a good chance to chat with not only the cPanel team but other hosting companies.  If you&amp;rsquo;re in the UK though it&amp;rsquo;s quite a trek and expense, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a smaller company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year as well as the main conference they&amp;rsquo;re also doing a series of one day conferences, some in the USA and then some outside of it.  One of those was in Edinburgh on 14th April 2016 and when they&amp;rsquo;re practically in your back yard it&amp;rsquo;d be rude not to go. So we (Dean and me) did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;not-london:ad21b4405288ae442b579089103a7bf3&#34;&gt;Not London&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay for not choosing London, almost everything seems to be in London (with the exception of a few bits in Manchester) when it comes to the internet in the UK.  It might be where most of the infrastructure is, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that&amp;rsquo;s where all the businesses who own that infrastructure are and it gets a bit boring going to London all the time.  Not everyone was happy at the choice, but I&amp;rsquo;d never been to Scotland before, so the location was a bonus to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>