<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self portrait on Me &amp; Life</title>
    <link>https://karlaustin.com/tags/self-portrait/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self portrait on Me &amp; Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="https://karlaustin.com/tags/self-portrait/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Self Portrait</title>
      <link>https://karlaustin.com/post/a-self-portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/a-self-portrait/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-s-not-easy&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not Easy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out it isn&amp;rsquo;t as easy to take a decent self portrait as you&amp;rsquo;d think.  Due to a number of factors I scrapped plans for my photo session today, but as it turned out I could actually do it but had no models, so the only one left was me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I take photos is so that I&amp;rsquo;m not in them, I don&amp;rsquo;t like having my photo taken and even though no one else was present it still took me some time to get even slightly comfortable being the subject of my photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-still-man&#34;&gt;Stay Still Man!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting yourself in the right position &amp;amp; pose each time you make a change is pretty much impossible, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve manually focused the camera as I did to start with.  Manual focus + long focal length + non-repeatable positioning = out of focus photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I was shooting with my camera connected to my laptop it was still tricky trying to balance, pose &amp;amp; lighting.  I don&amp;rsquo;t shoot using the live view mode, as I&amp;rsquo;ve never been happy with the results.  You really can&amp;rsquo;t beat the real-time feedback you get from looking through the viewfinder and seeing the effect the modelling lights have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did consider taking a bigger screen with me, but it was even more kit to load and unload so in the end I decided not to - I really should have taken it and also put some contact lenses in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;not-a-wasted-experience&#34;&gt;Not a Wasted Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I had no one else modelling for me, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a wasted session.  I still learnt a few lessons, which is what it&amp;rsquo;s all about right now, one of them being to have some spare modelling bulbs to hand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly then that though, I learnt that I really do need to get off my backside and join the gym, enough is enough.  I&amp;rsquo;ve put on about 12Kg (nearly 2 stone) since we got married at the end of 2012, it&amp;rsquo;s time that it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-results&#34;&gt;The Results&lt;/h1&gt;





</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>