<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Me &amp; Life</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/</link><description>Recent content on Me &amp; Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karlaustin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editing markdown on the go</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/editing-markdown-on-the-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/editing-markdown-on-the-go/</guid><description>Editing on iOS To make it easier for me to actually use my site and put things on it, one of the thing I wanted to do was edit from whatever device I happen to be on at the time. Most of the time when an idea pops in to my head that&amp;rsquo;s going to mean my phone (iPhone 13 Pro Max) or my iPad.
The options Having had a Google around for options the two they kept coming up the most were:</description></item><item><title>Github Actions and Workflows</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/github-actions-and-workflows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/github-actions-and-workflows/</guid><description>As per my Hello Again post I&amp;rsquo;m looking at automating some of my content creation.
The current state of play If you&amp;rsquo;ve looked before, you&amp;rsquo;ll know I use Hugo to build my site.
That means I need to ask Hugo to build my site whenever I add some more content, which currently means:
Get Hugo to build the content Update my git repo with the new content Push the repo to GitHub GitHub fires a webhook that tells my site to pull down new content Don&amp;rsquo;t shoot me, this was all build pre-workflow days.</description></item><item><title>Hello again</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/hello-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/hello-again/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while Erm&amp;hellip;. that&amp;rsquo;s an understatement, it&amp;rsquo;s been 5 years since I last put anything on here and it really is time I get back to it.
In an effort to do that I&amp;rsquo;m looking at how to make it easier for me to update whilst I&amp;rsquo;m on the go, so expect some content around that as I progress with it, watch this space as they say&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Juniper vMX CentOS i40e Driver Issues</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/juniper-vmx-centos-i40e-issues/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/juniper-vmx-centos-i40e-issues/</guid><description>vMX - Nice if you can make it work I like Juniper&amp;rsquo;s vMX product, I like JunOS and vMX makes it much more affordable to run inside your network.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t like is the rather sketchy documentation that gives the impression they&amp;rsquo;d rather you don&amp;rsquo;t run vMX. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that Ubuntu is their primary platform along with VMware now. They list support for Redhat and CentOS, but with CentOS at least there are some issues that the documentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover.</description></item><item><title>Negotiating With A Threenager</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/negotiating-with-a-threenager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 19:55:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/negotiating-with-a-threenager/</guid><description>We Don&amp;rsquo;t Negotiate With Terrorists or Threenagers Now don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, we really can&amp;rsquo;t complain with George, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many tantrums at all. I&amp;rsquo;d like to lay claim to that being down to me, but in reality it&amp;rsquo;s Karen and her DNA. Today however was one of those, &amp;ldquo;How can I be so heartless?&amp;rdquo; moments, as today there was no negotiation, it really was &amp;ldquo;Our way or our way&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>IPv6 at Home - It Should Not Be This Hard</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/ipv6-at-home-it-should-not-be-this-hard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 09:50:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/ipv6-at-home-it-should-not-be-this-hard/</guid><description>5Ghz Here We Come A few months ago I changed my home router from a Mikrotik RB2011 router to a Linksys WRT1900ACSv2 - Not a particularly cheap router, it&amp;rsquo;s still £ even now. I changed because I wanted 5Ghz wireless as the 2.4Ghz around here is massively congested, plus I wanted some faster speeds for copying photos to my NAS. I&amp;rsquo;ve got Gigabit wired to most rooms, but I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to find a cable most of the time to hook up to - I don&amp;rsquo;t usually have one long enough at home, work tends to stay at work these days.</description></item><item><title>Peertools: Automated notification of unsolicited BGP Open requests at peering points</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/peertools-automating-notification-of-potential-peers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 18:41:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/peertools-automating-notification-of-potential-peers/</guid><description>The Problem When you connect to an internet peering exchange, the IP addresses you&amp;rsquo;re given for your interfaces will most likely have been used by someone else prior to you, that has left the exchange.
This means, because we&amp;rsquo;re not all good at housekeeping, that you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with ISPs trying to open up BGP sessions with your routers and if you&amp;rsquo;re not firewalling them out then you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a lot of messages about BGP Opens being received from unconfigured neighbours.</description></item><item><title>Sample Packs from Printing Companies</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/printer-sample-packs-and-fail/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/printer-sample-packs-and-fail/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy the last couple of months putting things in place to get Ilumia Images up and running as its own business and as part of that I needed some printing done for business cards and some other items. I spent quite a bit of time on Google looking at options etc. and send off for sample print packs from 4 different printers
Printed.com Solopress.com digitalprinting.co.uk JAK Inc Delivery The first three of those all arrived within 3 days and all presented very nicely.</description></item><item><title>cPanel - Broken FTPS (FTP over TLS) with Java Clients</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve gone to edit your site and suddenly found that your chosen IDE won&amp;rsquo;t connect to upload any more via FTPS (FTP using TLS encryption) and your web host runs cPanel, then chances are they&amp;rsquo;re running v56 and your IDE is written in Java.
I hit this issue with another website late last week, where the DH params had already been re-generated to 2048 bit, but that change removed. Your IDE probably just says it can&amp;rsquo;t connect, that&amp;rsquo;s what JetBrains WebStorm and PhpStorm do although the logs did give more information:</description></item><item><title>Claiming a Facebook Page - Nightmare!</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</guid><description>What a PITA I&amp;rsquo;m the technical admin of the Whitwell Community Centre Facebook page. Every now and then someone will create a new Facebook Location for the centre and when we spot them, we merge them in to the main page, pretty standard stuff.
Don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy will you? Facebook don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy, this time it has been a right pain. I tried to merge the location in with the official page, unfortunately the official page wasn&amp;rsquo;t listed int he drop down of pages I could merge it with.</description></item><item><title>A Self Portrait</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/a-self-portrait/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/a-self-portrait/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s Not Easy It turns out it isn&amp;rsquo;t as easy to take a decent self portrait as you&amp;rsquo;d think. Due to a number of factors I scrapped plans for my photo session today, but as it turned out I could actually do it but had no models, so the only one left was me.
One of the reasons I take photos is so that I&amp;rsquo;m not in them, I don&amp;rsquo;t like having my photo taken and even though no one else was present it still took me some time to get even slightly comfortable being the subject of my photos.</description></item><item><title>Social Media Page Templates</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/social-media-page-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/social-media-page-templates/</guid><description>Every Interaction: Resources Page
If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to maintain a couple of Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn etc. pages you&amp;rsquo;ll know what a pain it can be when they keep changing how things look and the sizes you need for your header and profile images.
In updating a set of profiles for Ilumia Images yesterday I had that very same issue. Fortunately a quick search of Google brought me to the resources page of Every Interaction , a web design business based in London.</description></item><item><title>Wordpress, you're fired!</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/wordpress-youre-fired/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/wordpress-youre-fired/</guid><description>The Honeymoon Is Over Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out of the way now. I like Wordpress, I like how quick it is to get a site up and running and how easy it is to add functionality to a site. It&amp;rsquo;s going though.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Wordpress since around version 1.5, as have many of our customers at KDA. Whilst Wordpress is supposed to make things easier, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really. It just swaps some things you need to do, for another set of things you need to do instead.</description></item><item><title>Vallerret Photography Gloves - Initial Thoughts</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/vallerret-photography-gloves-initial-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/vallerret-photography-gloves-initial-thoughts/</guid><description>Vallerret Photography Gloves Vallerret Photography Gloves
I first came across the Vallerret Photography Gloves on Kickstarter back in December 2015 and today they were waiting for me when I got home from the coffee morning.
They got my attention as I&amp;rsquo;ve never found a pair of gloves that will keep my hands warm and allow me to operate my camera as well. It was either cold hands or fumbling with the camera, with the increased risk of dropping it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://karlaustin.com/about/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/about/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://karlaustin.com/work/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/work/work/</guid><description>Hello</description></item></channel></rss>