<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>internet on Me &amp; Life</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/tags/internet/</link><description>Recent content in internet on Me &amp; Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karlaustin.com/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Juniper vMX CentOS i40e Driver Issues</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/juniper-vmx-centos-i40e-issues/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/juniper-vmx-centos-i40e-issues/</guid><description>vMX - Nice if you can make it work I like Juniper&amp;rsquo;s vMX product, I like JunOS and vMX makes it much more affordable to run inside your network.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t like is the rather sketchy documentation that gives the impression they&amp;rsquo;d rather you don&amp;rsquo;t run vMX. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that Ubuntu is their primary platform along with VMware now. They list support for Redhat and CentOS, but with CentOS at least there are some issues that the documentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover.</description></item><item><title>IPv6 at Home - It Should Not Be This Hard</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/ipv6-at-home-it-should-not-be-this-hard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 09:50:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/ipv6-at-home-it-should-not-be-this-hard/</guid><description>5Ghz Here We Come A few months ago I changed my home router from a Mikrotik RB2011 router to a Linksys WRT1900ACSv2 - Not a particularly cheap router, it&amp;rsquo;s still £ even now. I changed because I wanted 5Ghz wireless as the 2.4Ghz around here is massively congested, plus I wanted some faster speeds for copying photos to my NAS. I&amp;rsquo;ve got Gigabit wired to most rooms, but I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to find a cable most of the time to hook up to - I don&amp;rsquo;t usually have one long enough at home, work tends to stay at work these days.</description></item><item><title>Peertools: Automated notification of unsolicited BGP Open requests at peering points</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/peertools-automating-notification-of-potential-peers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 18:41:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/peertools-automating-notification-of-potential-peers/</guid><description>The Problem When you connect to an internet peering exchange, the IP addresses you&amp;rsquo;re given for your interfaces will most likely have been used by someone else prior to you, that has left the exchange.
This means, because we&amp;rsquo;re not all good at housekeeping, that you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with ISPs trying to open up BGP sessions with your routers and if you&amp;rsquo;re not firewalling them out then you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a lot of messages about BGP Opens being received from unconfigured neighbours.</description></item><item><title>cPanel - Broken FTPS (FTP over TLS) with Java Clients</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve gone to edit your site and suddenly found that your chosen IDE won&amp;rsquo;t connect to upload any more via FTPS (FTP using TLS encryption) and your web host runs cPanel, then chances are they&amp;rsquo;re running v56 and your IDE is written in Java.
I hit this issue with another website late last week, where the DH params had already been re-generated to 2048 bit, but that change removed. Your IDE probably just says it can&amp;rsquo;t connect, that&amp;rsquo;s what JetBrains WebStorm and PhpStorm do although the logs did give more information:</description></item><item><title>Claiming a Facebook Page - Nightmare!</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</guid><description>What a PITA I&amp;rsquo;m the technical admin of the Whitwell Community Centre Facebook page. Every now and then someone will create a new Facebook Location for the centre and when we spot them, we merge them in to the main page, pretty standard stuff.
Don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy will you? Facebook don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy, this time it has been a right pain. I tried to merge the location in with the official page, unfortunately the official page wasn&amp;rsquo;t listed int he drop down of pages I could merge it with.</description></item></channel></rss>