<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fail on Me &amp; Life</title>
    <link>http://karlaustin.com/tags/fail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fail on Me &amp; Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://karlaustin.com/tags/fail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Packs from Printing Companies</title>
      <link>http://karlaustin.com/post/printer-sample-packs-and-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://karlaustin.com/post/printer-sample-packs-and-fail/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy the last couple of months putting things in place to get Ilumia Images up and running as its own business and as part of that I needed some printing done for business cards and some other items.  I spent quite a bit of time on Google looking at options etc. and send off for sample print packs from 4 different printers
 - Printed.com
 - Solopress.com
 - digitalprinting.co.uk
 - JAK Inc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivery:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three of those all arrived within 3 days and all presented very nicely.  The fourth, from JAK Ink arrived after 8 days, one day after I&amp;rsquo;d placed my order elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;printed-com:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Printed.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A clean white A5 envelope, with an A5 folder and a number of A5 sample sheets of paper in them.  The papers also had a nice touch on the back of them, showing how a set of colour swatches would be printed on to that paper, which I think is a great touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solopress-com:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Solopress.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solopress were the flashiest, sending out a perfect bound sample book of various papers and finishes in a metallic blue bubble envelope which I wish I&amp;rsquo;d taken a photograph of.  Not only did it show off their different papers and finishes very well, it also showcased their binding and felt very professional and something I could easily keep on my shelf for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;digitalprinting-co-uk:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;digitalprinting.co.uk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another folder, this time A4 inside the nice white envelope.  Inside the folder there were a selection of items such as business cards, stickers, compliment slips, postcards etc. that showed off their range of products and finishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;jak-inc:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;JAK Inc&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk about disappointing.  After waiting for a week after the first sample pack turned up I was expecting something a bit special, how wrong I was.  What I got was a small pink envelope with four postcard sized print samples and two business card samples inside.  The only indication of who these samples were from was the handwritten &amp;ldquo;Jak Inc&amp;rdquo; on the inside of the envelope flap.  For a company that makes products that are all about presentation and making a good impression, their first impressions were incredibly poor compared to their similarly priced competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-samples:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;The samples&lt;/h2&gt;




    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    &lt;div class=&#34;box alt&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;row uniform&#34;&gt;
        
        
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://karlaustin.com/img/2016/05/IMG_20160520_201623.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Printed.com&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;6u$&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://karlaustin.com/img/2016/05/IMG_20160520_201702.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;Solopress&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;6u&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://karlaustin.com/img/2016/05/IMG_20160520_201829.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;digitalprinting.co.uk&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
            
                &lt;div class=&#34;6u$&#34;&gt;
            
            
        
            
                
                    
                    &lt;span class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;
                
            
            
        
            
                
                        &lt;img src=&#39;http://karlaustin.com/img/2016/05/IMG_20160520_201927.jpg&#39;
                            alt=&#34;JAK Inc&#34; /&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
                
            
            
        
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;print-quality:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Print Quality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the samples were of a good quality with nothing really to chose between them, despite what my phone pictures above might be telling you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;decision:ef2502792fe86cfd8ea312fde2cb269d&#34;&gt;Decision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked Printed.com for my business cards, as only they and JAK Inc offered the velvet finish I wanted.  For the compliment slips and letterheads I went with Solopress as they were considerably cheaper than Printed.com and digitalprinting.co.uk.  Once everything arrives I&amp;rsquo;ll post up a review of both of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>