<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>website on Me &amp; Life</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/tags/website/</link><description>Recent content in website on Me &amp; Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karlaustin.com/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>cPanel - Broken FTPS (FTP over TLS) with Java Clients</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve gone to edit your site and suddenly found that your chosen IDE won&amp;rsquo;t connect to upload any more via FTPS (FTP using TLS encryption) and your web host runs cPanel, then chances are they&amp;rsquo;re running v56 and your IDE is written in Java.
I hit this issue with another website late last week, where the DH params had already been re-generated to 2048 bit, but that change removed. Your IDE probably just says it can&amp;rsquo;t connect, that&amp;rsquo;s what JetBrains WebStorm and PhpStorm do although the logs did give more information:</description></item><item><title>Claiming a Facebook Page - Nightmare!</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</guid><description>What a PITA I&amp;rsquo;m the technical admin of the Whitwell Community Centre Facebook page. Every now and then someone will create a new Facebook Location for the centre and when we spot them, we merge them in to the main page, pretty standard stuff.
Don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy will you? Facebook don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy, this time it has been a right pain. I tried to merge the location in with the official page, unfortunately the official page wasn&amp;rsquo;t listed int he drop down of pages I could merge it with.</description></item><item><title>Wordpress, you're fired!</title><link>https://karlaustin.com/post/wordpress-youre-fired/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karlaustin.com/post/wordpress-youre-fired/</guid><description>The Honeymoon Is Over Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out of the way now. I like Wordpress, I like how quick it is to get a site up and running and how easy it is to add functionality to a site. It&amp;rsquo;s going though.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Wordpress since around version 1.5, as have many of our customers at KDA. Whilst Wordpress is supposed to make things easier, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really. It just swaps some things you need to do, for another set of things you need to do instead.</description></item></channel></rss>