<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Me &amp; Life</title>
    <link>http://karlaustin.com/categories/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Me &amp; Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://karlaustin.com/categories/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>cPanel - Broken FTPS (FTP over TLS) with Java Clients</title>
      <link>http://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://karlaustin.com/post/cpanel-ftp-tls-and-the-java-devil/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve gone to edit your site and suddenly found that your chosen IDE won&amp;rsquo;t connect to upload any more via FTPS (FTP using TLS encryption) and your web host runs cPanel, then chances are they&amp;rsquo;re running v56 and your IDE is written in Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit this issue with another website late last week, where the DH params had already been re-generated to 2048 bit, but that change removed.  Your IDE probably just says it can&amp;rsquo;t connect, that&amp;rsquo;s what JetBrains WebStorm and PhpStorm do although the logs did give more information:
&lt;pre&gt;
Caused by: java.security.InvalidAlgorithmParameterException:
Prime size must be multiple of 64, and can only range from 512 to 2048 (inclusive)
&lt;/pre&gt;
NetBeans gave the game away sooner by giving the error from Java about DH parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weak-dh-keys:5636db6ebf579be2f27229e5248cab29&#34;&gt;Weak DH Keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The root cause of the issue is a problem with weak Diffie-Hellman key sizes, widely reported as the Logjam attack.  The recommendation is to move to 2048 bit prime number sizes which sounds brilliant, but then&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;damn-you-java:5636db6ebf579be2f27229e5248cab29&#34;&gt;Damn you Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only Java 8 supports 2048bit DH params, v7 supports a maximum of 1024bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big problem is that Java 8 supports only a &lt;em&gt;maximum&lt;/em&gt; of 2048bit, this is where we hit an issue with cPanel v56.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oops-cpanel:5636db6ebf579be2f27229e5248cab29&#34;&gt;Oops cPanel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that on April 20th 2016 cPanel pushed out an update that generated new dhparams for pure-ftpd, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand the warnings around Java, as they generated 3072 bit DH params, which you can verify with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
openssl dh -in /etc/ssl/private/pure-ftpd-dhparams.pem -text -noout
&lt;/pre&gt;
You&amp;rsquo;ll see output like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Diffie-Hellman-Parameters: (3072 bit)
    prime:
        00:80:26:5e:fe:c9:8e:63:2d:6d:52:3e:ab:4c:49:
        &lt;snip&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
As you can see, 3072 bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixing-it:5636db6ebf579be2f27229e5248cab29&#34;&gt;Fixing it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the fix is easy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
cp /etc/ssl/private/pure-ftpd-dhparams.pem /etc/ssl/private/pure-ftpd-dhparams.pem.bak
openssl dhparam -out /etc/ssl/private/pure-ftpd-dhparams.pem 2048
service pure-ftpd restart
&lt;/pre&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;ve backed up the existing params just in case and generated new ones for pure-ftpd to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;will-it-break-again:5636db6ebf579be2f27229e5248cab29&#34;&gt;Will it break again?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That remains to be seen.  The issue has been reported to cPanel, so hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t break as we&amp;rsquo;re not just talking a few IDEs here like JetBrains, NetBeans etc. there are also countless ERP systems out there that use Java and a lot of them shuffle files (such as orders, tracking info for shipping) in and out via FTP with their customers and suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claiming a Facebook Page - Nightmare!</title>
      <link>http://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://karlaustin.com/post/facebook-claiming-a-page/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-a-pita:b7f47509e66c6c65a88ac76589690692&#34;&gt;What a PITA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the technical admin of the 

    
        
    

    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitwellcommunitycentre.com&#34; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;Whitwell Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;

 Facebook page.  Every now and then someone will create a new Facebook Location for the centre and when we spot them, we merge them in to the main page, pretty standard stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-make-it-easy-will-you:b7f47509e66c6c65a88ac76589690692&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy will you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook don&amp;rsquo;t make it easy, this time it has been a right pain.  I tried to merge the location in with the official page, unfortunately the official page wasn&amp;rsquo;t listed int he drop down of pages I could merge it with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an alternative I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just try and claim it as the owner, part of that is adding an email address from the organisation to your profile.  Easy enough right? &lt;em&gt;Oh no&lt;/em&gt;, my email address is in the form of &lt;code&gt;admin@&lt;/code&gt; which Facebook promptly told me isn&amp;rsquo;t a valid email address - which is funny, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting email at it for several years now.  So off I pop to configure a different email address, which Facebook then willingly accepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking that this might have changed the merge outcome I have another go, &lt;em&gt;nope&lt;/em&gt;, still not listed in the drop down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook do say that the pages need to have similar names (they have exactly the same name) and be of the same type.  Now trying to work out how to get the official page to say just &amp;ldquo;Community Centre&amp;rdquo; is what was fun, it took 30 minutes of experimenting to work that one out, trying different combinations of types and sub-categories. Why I can&amp;rsquo;t just type in &amp;ldquo;Community Centre&amp;rdquo; and it suggest the appropriate options I will never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;arghhhhh:b7f47509e66c6c65a88ac76589690692&#34;&gt;Arghhhhh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have everything matching, the name, the type of organisation and yet it &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t list the official page in the drop down for me to merge it with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How a company with so many developers and experts in their field can make such a user hostile system I will never know. It should not be this difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-hope:b7f47509e66c6c65a88ac76589690692&#34;&gt;Final Hope&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final hope is that having added an organisation email address and submitted a claim for admin rights on the page, that I will be able to merge it in with the official page.  &lt;em&gt;Fingers crossed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>